Josh Zimmerman

Brooklyn, NY | 561-502-3832 | JZimmsCodes@outlook.com

Github: JZims | Blog: zimmerman-j.medium.com | Personal Portfolio: https://joshzimmerman.netlify.app/

JOB TITLE

Full-stack Software Engineer with experience working in JavaScript and React libraries as frontend, and Ruby on Rails for API applications. Being a Food and Wine Industry Professional for 8+ years allows me the strict tenets of being consistent to an unwavering degree. A natural innovator, a constant re-inventor and firm believer in the importance of adapting in order to overcome.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript • C++ • Go • ReactJS • Ruby On Rails • SQL • PostgreSQL • ORM-Data Models • JSON • HTML • CSS Backbone.JS • Redux • Node.JS • Heroku • Netlify • Git Workflow

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Beverage Inventory and Order Management Environment (B.I.O.M.E.) - Github | Demo

A single-page application for organizing and ordering product from a beverage manager standpoint

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side.
- Configured Redux within React to store and manage all stately data
- Created a manifest system for updating many items on the backend with just one call to the API
- Utilized React Bootstrap to keep the application to a single page in order to keep a lightweight appearance

UOweMe - Github | Demo

A playful application used to keep track of money owed to you by others for various deeds

- Collaborated with a fellow programmer to make a practical planning app for both comedic relief and usefulness
- Utilized React Router to allow for smoother navigation around the site
- Leveraged JSON Server to provide a simplified API for CRUD
- Deployed the entire application using Heroku for the backend JSON server and Netlify for the React frontend

DeckSwap - Github | Demo

An application geared towards Magic: the Gathering enthusiasts, allowing users to rent pre-constructed decks from each other

- Incorporated basic Ruby code to make backend architecture straightforward and clean
- Implemented many tools available in the vast toolbelt of React to create a dynamic user experience
- Worked with multiple asynchronous functions to make a series of intricate calls from the front end to the backend
- Utilized external API calls from established websites with permission via API keys, which enhanced the overall user experience

EXPERIENCE

Domenico Valentino Selections

NYC, NY

Field Sales Representative

07/2019 - 03/2020

- Composed hundreds of well-written sales pitches to attract an ever-expanding customer base each week
- Nurtured relationship-based accounts spanning all of Manhattan and Brooklyn, creating a steady flow of business

Some Good Wine

NYC, NY

Web Content Manager / Sales

07/2017 - 08/2019

- Developed a web platform using BevMedia and a Shopify API to create an immersive shopping platform
- Responsible for the ordering of wines and education during customer tasting events

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY

Full Stack Software Engineer

03/2021 - 06/2021

The Culinary Institute of America

Hyde Park, NY

B.S. // Food Science

02/2012 - 11/2015